news-miner.com 2002-01-27

# Fairbanks Daily News-Miner

---  

 Alaska News  
  Home Page  
  Headlines  
  Local News  
  Sports Headlines  
  Statewide News  
  Obituaries  
  Editorial Headlines  
  Letters to the Editor  
  Today's Cole Column  

 Columnists  
  Dan O'Neill  
  Judy Kleinfeld  
  Gary Moore  
| 

|    
|  | **General Privacy Policy**  
---  
  
**The newspaper is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers. The following statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Web site.**

**What personally identifiable information does the website collect from me?**  
Information is collected in several ways. Some personal information is gathered through server log files. Personal information is also gathered when you enter a contest or promotion, request vacation delivery stop, or when you post an online ad. During these instances, denverpost.com asks for information such as your name, e-mail address, street address, zip code, phone number, subscriber status, and credit card number. We may also ask you for other information at other times. Whenever we collect information about you, we will make an effort to link to our privacy policy.   
  
**How is my information used?**  
Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a customized experience. Denverpost.com uses information collected from server log files, such as IP addresses, to help diagnose problems with our services, to administer our Web site, and to report and gather aggregate information about site usage and user demographics. The aggregated data may be shared with advertisers or business partners. 

Cookies are used to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web service and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are used to deliver targeted advertising based on your behavior or demographics and to track your number of entries in some of our promotions and contests. You can set your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but if you do we will not be able to customize the Web site's features according to your preferences. Advertising networks that serve ads into our site, such as Real Media or DoubleClick, may also use their own cookies. For more information about Real Media's use of cookies, visit <http://www.realmedia.com/privacy.html>. For more information about DoubleClick's use of cookies, visit [http://www. privacychoices.org](http://www.%20privacychoices.org/). 

**With whom is my information shared?**  
When you are on an area of the Web site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with the newspaper and its related companies. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any other company, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Promotions and contests that run on the newspaper Web site may be sponsored by companies other than the newspaper Web site or may be co-sponsored by the newspaper Web site and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion or contest may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion or contest if you don't want your data to be shared. 

The newspaper may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to our Web site users. Some of these forums require registration. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

Aggregate information compiled by the newspaper Web site may be shared with advertisers and business partners as well as used by the newspaper and its related companies. 

**Linked Sites**  
Please be aware that the newspaper Web site's promotional partners, advertisers, sponsors, third-party Internet sites, and content providers accessible through denverpost.com may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. The newspaper and Web site are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third party parties. Users should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing personally identifiable information through co-sponsored, affiliated or linked sites. 

**Children's Guidelines**  
The Newspaper in Education program is a free service the newspaper may offer for teachers which promotes the use of newspapers in the classroom. The information requested on these pages is used solely for participation in the particular activity, and is not stored or sold to third parties. If a question, comment, story, joke, idea or opinion is published, only the student's first name, grade and state/country appear on the site. Students are advised to consult with their parents before giving personal information online. 

**Children's Privacy Policy**  
  
The newspaper is committed to complying with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. Because many visitors to this site are children, we employ special measures to help children protect their privacy while online. The newspaper does not ask children to disclose more personal information than is necessary for them to participate in a particular activity. We urge children to check with their parents before entering information on any website and we urge parents to discuss with their children restrictions regarding the online release of personal information to anyone they don't know. 

To help ensure a rewarding online experience for parents and children, we provide this summary of our information practices. As we continue to offer our visitors new and different types of content and services, we may modify our practices from time to time. However, we will treat all personal information we collect in accordance with the privacy notice in effect at the time the information is collected. 

**Information Collected**  
The newspaper does not collect personal information online from children under 13 without their parent's consent, except in special limited circumstances. Generally, the newspaper limits its collection of information from children to what is known as nonpersonally identifiable information (e.g. screen names, birthday, gender, city, state, zip code and country of residence). This information is collected so children can participate in activities (e.g. completing polls or online surveys, posting jokes, book reviews, movie reviews, toy reviews, video reviews, concert reviews, game reviews, artwork or questions/comments online, or playing online games) without giving unnecessary personal information. From time to time, however, we may request limited personally identifiable information (e.g. child's email address and/or parent's or guardian's email address), as explained below, in order to conduct online contests or sweepstakes or offer other online activities. The newspaper does not condition a child's participation in any of our online activities on the disclosure of more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. 

**Contest and Sweepstakes**  
The newspaper occasionally offers contest and sweepstakes, which may be entered online. When a child under thirteen enters a contest or sweepstakes, or participates in another activity that requires the use of personal information, we will ask for a parent's email address so that we can notify the parent of the child's entry and give the parent the option to have the child's entry deleted. All personally identifiable information collected by the newspaper is securely maintained and used only for the purpose of conducting the contest or sweepstakes. Once the contest or sweepstakes is finished, the newspaper will delete any personal information collected. 

**Use of Information**  
The newspaper uses personally identifiable information provided by children for conducting contests or sweepstakes. The newspaper uses parents' email addresses to notify them when we have received information from their children and to give parents the option to remove their child's information. The newspaper does not keep any personal information obtained through a contest or sweepstakes after the particular event is completed. Sometimes, we use agents or contractors to provide services, such as helping us conduct a sweepstakes or sending prizes to winners. In these cases, we require the agent or contractor to keep the information confidential and to use it only for the specific services they are performing. 

The newspaper may disclose information maintained as required by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. The newspaper may also disclose such information in response to a specific law enforcement agency's request. 

**Cookies**  
The newspaper uses a software technology called "cookies." Cookies are small files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Cookies themselves do not contain any personally identifiable information. Although cookies could enable the newspaper to relate a visitor's use of this website to personal information that the visitor has provided, such as an email address, we do not use cookies for this purpose. We do use cookies to determine how many visitors we have and how often they visit various sections of our site. You can, of course, disable cookies on your computer by indicating this in the preferences or options menus in your browser. 

**Parental Access**  
Parents, please send a letter or postcard to our Privacy Coordinator at the mailing address provided below if you would like to do any of the following: 

  * Access personally identifiable information that the newspaper has collected online from your child,
  * Correct factual errors in such information,
  * Request to have this information deleted, or
  * Request that we no longer collect or maintain such information.

Please include your email address and telephone number where we can reach you. The newspaper takes steps to verify the identity of anyone requesting information about a child and to ensure that the person is in fact the child's parent or legal guardian.   

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our privacy policy and/or practices, please send an e-mail to [feedback@newschoice.com](mailto:feedback@newschoice.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Feedback%20\(FbkMnr\)).   

* * *

© 1999-2001 MediaNews Group, Inc. and Fairbanks Publishing Company, Inc. | 

| Privacy Policy  
---  

  Change of Address  
  Delivery Problems  
  Vacation Stop  
   
 Lifestyles  
   
 Featured Channels  
  
---  

 Alaska News  
  Home Page  
  Headlines  
  Local News  
  Sports Headlines  
  Statewide News  
  Obituaries  
  Editorial Headlines  
  Letters to the Editor  
  Today's Cole Column  

  Sun - Business News  

 Columnists  
  Dan O'Neill  
  Gary Moore  
| 

|    
|  | **General Privacy Policy**  
---  
  
**The newspaper is committed to protecting the privacy of our customers. The following statement discloses our information gathering and dissemination practices for the Web site.**

**What personally identifiable information does the website collect from me?**  
Information is collected in several ways. Some personal information is gathered through server log files. Personal information is also gathered when you enter a contest or promotion, request vacation delivery stop, or when you post an online ad. During these instances, denverpost.com asks for information such as your name, e-mail address, street address, zip code, phone number, subscriber status, and credit card number. We may also ask you for other information at other times. Whenever we collect information about you, we will make an effort to link to our privacy policy.   
  
**How is my information used?**  
Our primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you with a customized experience. Denverpost.com uses information collected from server log files, such as IP addresses, to help diagnose problems with our services, to administer our Web site, and to report and gather aggregate information about site usage and user demographics. The aggregated data may be shared with advertisers or business partners. 

Cookies are used to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from a Web service and stored on your computer's hard drive. Cookies are used to deliver targeted advertising based on your behavior or demographics and to track your number of entries in some of our promotions and contests. You can set your browser to refuse to accept cookies, but if you do we will not be able to customize the Web site's features according to your preferences. Advertising networks that serve ads into our site, such as Real Media or DoubleClick, may also use their own cookies. For more information about Real Media's use of cookies, visit <http://www.realmedia.com/privacy.html>. For more information about DoubleClick's use of cookies, visit [http://www. privacychoices.org](http://www.%20privacychoices.org/). 

**With whom is my information shared?**  
When you are on an area of the Web site and are asked for personal information, you are sharing that information with the newspaper and its related companies. If data is being collected and/or maintained by any other company, you will be notified prior to the time of the data collection or transfer. If you do not want your data to be shared, you can choose not to allow the transfer by not using that particular service. 

Promotions and contests that run on the newspaper Web site may be sponsored by companies other than the newspaper Web site or may be co-sponsored by the newspaper Web site and another company. Some or all data collected during a promotion or contest may be shared with the sponsor. If data will be shared, you will be notified prior to the time of data collection or transfer. You can decide not to participate in the promotion or contest if you don't want your data to be shared. 

The newspaper may make chat rooms, forums, message boards, and/or news groups available to our Web site users. Some of these forums require registration. Please remember that any information that is disclosed in these areas becomes public information and you should exercise caution when deciding to disclose your personal information. 

Aggregate information compiled by the newspaper Web site may be shared with advertisers and business partners as well as used by the newspaper and its related companies. 

**Linked Sites**  
Please be aware that the newspaper Web site's promotional partners, advertisers, sponsors, third-party Internet sites, and content providers accessible through denverpost.com may have their own privacy and data collection policies and practices. The newspaper and Web site are not responsible for any actions or policies of such third party parties. Users should check the applicable privacy policies of those third parties when providing personally identifiable information through co-sponsored, affiliated or linked sites. 

**Children's Guidelines**  
The Newspaper in Education program is a free service the newspaper may offer for teachers which promotes the use of newspapers in the classroom. The information requested on these pages is used solely for participation in the particular activity, and is not stored or sold to third parties. If a question, comment, story, joke, idea or opinion is published, only the student's first name, grade and state/country appear on the site. Students are advised to consult with their parents before giving personal information online. 

**Children's Privacy Policy**  
  
The newspaper is committed to complying with the Children's Online Privacy Protection Act of 1998. Because many visitors to this site are children, we employ special measures to help children protect their privacy while online. The newspaper does not ask children to disclose more personal information than is necessary for them to participate in a particular activity. We urge children to check with their parents before entering information on any website and we urge parents to discuss with their children restrictions regarding the online release of personal information to anyone they don't know. 

To help ensure a rewarding online experience for parents and children, we provide this summary of our information practices. As we continue to offer our visitors new and different types of content and services, we may modify our practices from time to time. However, we will treat all personal information we collect in accordance with the privacy notice in effect at the time the information is collected. 

**Information Collected**  
The newspaper does not collect personal information online from children under 13 without their parent's consent, except in special limited circumstances. Generally, the newspaper limits its collection of information from children to what is known as nonpersonally identifiable information (e.g. screen names, birthday, gender, city, state, zip code and country of residence). This information is collected so children can participate in activities (e.g. completing polls or online surveys, posting jokes, book reviews, movie reviews, toy reviews, video reviews, concert reviews, game reviews, artwork or questions/comments online, or playing online games) without giving unnecessary personal information. From time to time, however, we may request limited personally identifiable information (e.g. child's email address and/or parent's or guardian's email address), as explained below, in order to conduct online contests or sweepstakes or offer other online activities. The newspaper does not condition a child's participation in any of our online activities on the disclosure of more information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. 

**Contest and Sweepstakes**  
The newspaper occasionally offers contest and sweepstakes, which may be entered online. When a child under thirteen enters a contest or sweepstakes, or participates in another activity that requires the use of personal information, we will ask for a parent's email address so that we can notify the parent of the child's entry and give the parent the option to have the child's entry deleted. All personally identifiable information collected by the newspaper is securely maintained and used only for the purpose of conducting the contest or sweepstakes. Once the contest or sweepstakes is finished, the newspaper will delete any personal information collected. 

**Use of Information**  
The newspaper uses personally identifiable information provided by children for conducting contests or sweepstakes. The newspaper uses parents' email addresses to notify them when we have received information from their children and to give parents the option to remove their child's information. The newspaper does not keep any personal information obtained through a contest or sweepstakes after the particular event is completed. Sometimes, we use agents or contractors to provide services, such as helping us conduct a sweepstakes or sending prizes to winners. In these cases, we require the agent or contractor to keep the information confidential and to use it only for the specific services they are performing. 

The newspaper may disclose information maintained as required by law, for example, in response to a court order or a subpoena. The newspaper may also disclose such information in response to a specific law enforcement agency's request. 

**Cookies**  
The newspaper uses a software technology called "cookies." Cookies are small files that we place in visitors' computer browsers to store their preferences. Cookies themselves do not contain any personally identifiable information. Although cookies could enable the newspaper to relate a visitor's use of this website to personal information that the visitor has provided, such as an email address, we do not use cookies for this purpose. We do use cookies to determine how many visitors we have and how often they visit various sections of our site. You can, of course, disable cookies on your computer by indicating this in the preferences or options menus in your browser. 

**Parental Access**  
Parents, please send a letter or postcard to our Privacy Coordinator at the mailing address provided below if you would like to do any of the following: 

  * Access personally identifiable information that the newspaper has collected online from your child,
  * Correct factual errors in such information,
  * Request to have this information deleted, or
  * Request that we no longer collect or maintain such information.

Please include your email address and telephone number where we can reach you. The newspaper takes steps to verify the identity of anyone requesting information about a child and to ensure that the person is in fact the child's parent or legal guardian.   

**Contact Us**  
If you have any questions, comments or concerns regarding our privacy policy and/or practices, please send an e-mail to [feedback@newschoice.com](mailto:feedback@newschoice.com?Subject=Privacy%20Policy%20Feedback%20\(FbkMnr\)).   

* * *

© 1999-2002 MediaNews Group, Inc. and Fairbanks Publishing Company, Inc. | 

| Privacy Policy  
---  

  Change of Address  
  Delivery Problems  
  Vacation Stop  
   
 Lifestyles  
   
 Featured Channels
